<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>On Taking Notes</title>
<link>https://recleev.github.io/on-taking-notes/</link>
<atom:link href="https://recleev.github.io/on-taking-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Recle&#39;s blog about taking handwritten notes</description>
<generator>quarto-1.7.33</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 16:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Why Write About Taking Notes</title>
  <dc:creator>Recle E. Vibal</dc:creator>
  <link>https://recleev.github.io/on-taking-notes/posts/why-write-about-taking-notes/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<div class="note-with-text">
<div class="note">
<p><img src="https://recleev.github.io/on-taking-notes/posts/why-write-about-taking-notes/why-write-about-taking-notes_Page_1.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Why write about taking notes, handwritten page 1."></p>
</div>
<div class="text">
<p>I have been taking notes ever since I learned to write. Most of my teachers in elementary and high school required and checked notes. I initially thought it was weird to force note taking on children, but it became a habit and a skill I carried through high education and in my professional life.</p>
<p>I take notes mostly during lectures and sometimes when journaling. I, and some of my classmates <sup>-</sup>, use my notes to study for exams. I think I did pretty well in school. Taking note of things that I find interesting, paraphrasing the lesson as I see or hear it, and having the opportunity to review it anytime might have helped my studies.</p>
<p>When I started working, I had</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="note-with-text">
<div class="note">
<p><img src="https://recleev.github.io/on-taking-notes/posts/why-write-about-taking-notes/why-write-about-taking-notes_Page_2.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Why write about taking notes, handwritten page 2."></p>
</div>
<div class="text">
<p>to commute a lot, and I had little opportunity to take notes. Well, at least the handwritten ones. With the rise of smartphones and my work that involved a screen and keyboard, my few opportunities of taking notes were relegated to typewritten documents. It is still note taking, but I missed my pen and paper.</p>
<p>A little later, I discovered the <a href="bulletjournal.com">bullet journal</a>. It fit my lifestyle then; I still do it. I was writing daily again. When I changed career, I was involved in more meetings and more learning opportunities, the bullet journal turned into a companion in life and learning.</p>
<p>What’s my point?</p>
<p>After all these years taking notes,</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="note-with-text">
<div class="note">
<p><img src="https://recleev.github.io/on-taking-notes/posts/why-write-about-taking-notes/why-write-about-taking-notes_Page_3.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Why write about taking notes, handwritten page 3."></p>
</div>
<div class="text">
<p>I thought it is a skill that everyone knows how to use. But that does not seem to be the case. I had friends that photocopied my notes. I judged them to be lazy note takers, but maybe they really don’t know how to take notes. I know someone who admitted they did not know how to take notes. At first, I found that odd. Then I thought how amazing it would be for these people to learn the power and joy of taking notes.</p>
<p>I believe taking notes is an art and a science. It requires skill. It is also fun. And in case it is not obvious, I prefer taking hand written notes. A pen gliding on a surface captures my thoughts and my emotions better than fingertips slamming a key cap. I am genera­lizing here because I also write</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="note-with-text">
<div class="note">
<p><img src="https://recleev.github.io/on-taking-notes/posts/why-write-about-taking-notes/why-write-about-taking-notes_Page_4.png" class="img-fluid" alt="Why write about taking notes, handwritten page 4."></p>
</div>
<div class="text">
<p>using e- ink on my <a href="supernote.com">Supernote</a></p>
<p>In short, I write about taking handwritten notes because I love writing. Through this writing, I hope my passion on taking handwri­tten notes would infect and convince more people that everyone should take notes.</p>
</div>
</div>



<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents" id="quarto-reuse"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Reuse</h2><div class="quarto-appendix-contents"><div><a rel="license" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">CC BY 4.0</a></div></div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>posts</category>
  <category>notes</category>
  <category>writing</category>
  <category>personal</category>
  <guid>https://recleev.github.io/on-taking-notes/posts/why-write-about-taking-notes/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
